Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory7 Mss.B.B61.inventory07
American Philosophical Society
Franz Boas Papers: Inventory (I-K)
1862-1942
Mss.B.B61.inventory07
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the Franz Boas Papers (Mss B B61). For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Scope and Contents note
Due to the size of the collection, the content for Series I has been divided into multiple inventories. Please follow the links below to browse the inventories.
Inventories
Correspondents A
Correspondents B
Correspondents C
Correspondents D
Correspondents E-G
Correspondents H
Correspondents I-K
Correspondents L
Correspondents M
Correspondents N-Q
Correspondents R
Correspondents S
Correspondents T-V
Correspondents W-Z
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents I
  - I, Ferdinand (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1932 Aug. 6
  - Ickes, Harold L. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 3; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 30; 1p.
    - H.L. Ickes -- from R.C. Moley, 1933 Mar. 24
    - (Enc. with Moley, R.C., Mar. 24, 1933)
  - Iglehart, R. Lannert (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 11; 2p.
    - R. Lannert Iglehart -- to Columbia Univ., 1933 Apr. 17; 1p.
      Scope and Contents note
      (Attached: a memorandum from Office of the Secretary)
  - Ihlseng, O. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1918 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - O. Ihlseng -- to P.E. Goddard, 1918 Jan. 2; 1p.
  - Illinois Publishing Co. (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 26
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 30
    - To Boas, 1917 Aug. 5
  - Iltis, Hugo (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1938 June 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 June 9; 1p.
  - "El Imparcial" (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 16
  - "In Fact". Editor (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1941 Oct. 30; 1p.
      (Enc: statement)
  - Independent Citizens' Committee for Lehman and Poletti (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 2; 1p.
  - Index of literature (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec.; 1p.
  - Indiana Historical Society (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1939 May 22; 1p.
  - Ingersoll, Marion C. (Mrs. R.V.) (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 14; 1p.
  - Ingraham, Mrs. Henry H. (Box 46)
    - From Boas
    - See Boas, F. to Lombardo, C.J., Oct. 14, 1940.
  - Inhulsen, C.H.P. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1927 May 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 14; 2p.
  - Innsbruck, Austria (Pres. of Ferdinandeum) (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1922 Nov. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1922 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 5; 1p.
  - Institut für angewandte Soziologie (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 21; 1p.
  - Institut international de coopération intellectuale (Box 46)
    - From Luchaire, J., 1928 Dec. 3
    - To Secrétaire général from Luchaire, J., 1928 Dec. 3
  - Institute for Comparative Research in Human Culture (Box 46)
    - See Schenke, W., Jan. 15, 1925
    - From Nansen, F., 1926 Apr. 12
    - To Laura Spelman Rockefeller, 1925 Oct. 7; 10p.
  - Institute of International Education (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 15
    - From Eisenmenger, Walter S., 1920 Apr. 24; 1p.
      See Waite, Mary L. Duggan, Stephan P. Russell, William L.
  - Institute of race relations (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 25; 4p.
    - (Enc: Friends, Society of Committee on race relations. Preliminary statement regarding the institute of race relations.), 1935 July 1-29; 3p.
  - Instituto Politecnico Nacional (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1939 May 15; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1939 May 15; 5p.
  - Institutum Anthropologium Universitatis Jagellonicae (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1937 May 10; 1p.
  - Intercollegiate Russian Students of America (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1942 Nov. 30; 1p.
  - International Academy of Sciences at Jerusalem (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1940 Jan. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec.
  - International auxiliary language association in U.S. (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1930 Apr.; 3p.
  - International congress for studies regarding population, Rome (Box 46)
    - See Gini, C., Feb. 10, 1931.
  - International congress of Americanists (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1927 May 2; 1p.
    - [Announc.ofmeeting, 1928 Sept. 17-22; 2p.
    - [program & membership], 1928 Sept. 17-22; 2p.
    - [general program], 1928 Sept. 17-22; 4p.
    - [countries invited], 1928 Sept. 17-22; 1p.
    - [officers], 1928 Sept. 17-22; 4p.
    - [preliminary program], 1928 Sept. 17-22; 4p.
    - [speech of welcome], 1928 Sept. 17-22; 5p.
  - International Congress of Anthropologists, 1888 (Box 46)
    - To Boas from Brinton, D.G., Jan. 27
    - To Boas from Mann, E.C., Feb. 11
    - To Boas from Powell, J.W., Feb. 9
    - To Boas from Newell, W.W., Apr. 18
    - To Boas from Newell, W.W., Apr. 20
    - To Boas from Raymond, J.H., Apr. 26
    - To Boas from Mann, E.C., Apr. 25
    - From Boas, 1888 Feb. 14
  - International congress of anthropology and prehistoric archaeology (Box 46)
    - See Myres, J.L., Jan. 24, 1931.
  - International Congress of Cosmobiology -- (1st) (Box 46)
    - See Barail, LouisC., Feb. 28, 1938
  - International Congress of Eugenics -- (3rd) (Box 46)
    - See Boas, F. to Laughlin, H.H., June 28, 1932.
  - International Congress of Glottology (Linguistics) (Box 46)
    - See enclosure in Walt? W., Mar. 31, 1933; (3d)
  - International congress of linguists (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1928 Apr. 10; (1st)
    - See Bally, C., 1930 Oct. 4; (2d)
    - Enc. with MacCurdy, 1931 Mar. 16; (2d)
  - International congress of mental hygiene -- (1st) (Box 46)
    - Enc. with Williams, F.E., Oct. 30, 1929
  - International Coordinating Comm. for Aid to Refugees (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 25; 1p.
  - International Education Board (Box 46)
    See Shepardson, Whitney H.
  - International Genetics Congress -- (7th) (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1939 Aug. 22-30; 4p.
  - International institute of African language and culture (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr 21; 1p
    - See Brackett, D.W. Oct. 11, 1928, 1934 Apr. 3; receipt
  - International institute of anthropology and prehistoric archaeology -- (15th) (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 15; 6p.
  - International journal of American linguistics (Box 46)
    - See Boas, F., 1917 Dec.
    - From Faxon, F.W. Co., 1920 Oct. 21; 1p.
    - To Pearl, R., 1931 Oct. 6
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan. 1
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec.
  - International Labor Defense (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 28; 1p.
  - International league for academic freedom (Box 46)
    - Enc. with Kallen, H.M., Jan. 31, 1934
  - International league for truth in Germany (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 May 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, May 3, 1939.
  - International League of Arts & Sciences (Box 46)
    - See Anon., 1928 June 28
  - International philosophic society (Box 46)
    - See Schmid, R., Sept. 7, 1929
  - International School of American Archaeology (Box 46)
    - See Meyer, E., June 18, 1913
    - Boas, F. to Seler, E.G., June 26, 1913
    - Seler, E.G., July 23, 1913
    - Seler, E.G. to Trottza Solz v., July 24, 1913.
    - Seler, E.G., July 10, 1913
    - Boas, F. to Seler, E.G., Aug. 7, 1913
    - Wagner, M.L., Sept. 1, 1913
    - Wagner, M.L., Sept. 14, 1913
    - Wagner, M.L., Oct. 8, 1913
    - Wagner, M.L., Nov. 11, 1913
    - Wagner, M.L., Nov. 26, 1913
    - Wagner, M.L., Dec. 15, 1913
    - Wagner, M.L., Dec. 30, 1913
  - International School of American Archeology & Ethnology (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1910 Dec.
    - To Boas, 1911 Nov. 28; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec.; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec.; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 13; 7p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec.; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Mar. 2
    - To Boas, 1914 July 10
    - To Boas, 1914 Oct. 19; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1915 Dec.; 10p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Oct. 19; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Nov. 19; 2p.
    - Enc. with Boas, F. to Graves, M., 1939 June 5; 2p.
    - To Huntington, A.M., 1911 Jan. 6; 2p.
  - International sociological congress -- (4th) (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec.; 4p.
  - International Young Men's Christian Association College (Box 46)
    See Cureton, T.K., Jr.
  - Internationale Hilfsvereinigung. Auslands Komite (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Jul. 17; 1p
  - Internationale Wochenschrift für Wissenschaft, Kunst & Technik (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1908 Oct. 15
  - Internationaler Americanister Kongress -- 21 (Box 46)
    - Enc: Lehmann, W., Nov. 6, 1924
  - Inverarity, R.B. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1941 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Mar.; 1p.
  - Iowa State University Serial Department (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1941 Oct. 3
  - Ippolito, C. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 29; 2p.
  - Ireland, M.W. (Box 46)
    - M.W. Ireland -- to F.P. Keppel, 1918 Nov. 5; 1p.
  - Irish, W.E. (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 6; 1p.
  - Ironside, Nestor (Box 46)
    - 1715 June 15, 1p.
    - (Enc. with Efron, David, July 5, 1938)
    - N. Ironside -- from Johannes Misochirosophus, 1713 June 12
    - (Enc. with Efron, David, July 5, 1938)
  - Irons, Hubert D. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Apr. 9; 1p.
  - Irvine, B.F. (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1917 Nov. 13
    - B.F. Irvine -- to G. Creel, 1918 Mar. 22; 2p.
    - (Enc. originally with Fracktenberg, L.J. to Boas, F., Apr. 1, 1918)
    - B.F. Irvine -- to J.C. Tumulty, 1917 Nov. 13
  - Irving Press (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1904 Dec. 14; 1p.
  - Irwin, Theodore (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1938 June 14; 1p.
  - Isaacs, S.M. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 18; 1p.
  - Isaacson, C.D. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1931 Sept. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Sept. 2; 1p.
  - Israel, Anna Luise (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1923 Aug. 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Aug. 16; 2p.
  - Israel Matz Foundation (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 2; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 11; 1p.
  - Isserman, Abraham J. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1941 Sept. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Mar. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - (Enc: Clipping North, Joseph (open letter) n.d.), 1941 Sept. 15; 1p.
  - Italia Steamship Co. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 29; 1p.
  - Italy America Society (Box 46)
    See Arbib-Costa, A.
  - Itubemann? (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1913 Apr. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Mar. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 29; 1p.
  - Ives, C.P. (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1931 May 11; 2p.
  - Ives, Irving M. (Box 46)
    - From Boas
    - See Boas, F. to Hanley, J.R., Mar. 2, 1942.
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 9; 1p.
  - Iyer, L.K. A. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 24; 1p.
  - Izikowitz, K.G. (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1932 July 23; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Sept. 23; 2p.
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents J
  - J?? (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 7; 1p.
      (Director of Staatsuniversiteit to Gent.)
  - Jaches, L. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1935 Jan. 16; 1p.
  - Jackson, Anthony G. (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1939 June 10; 1p.
      (Enc: Anti-Ism League of America. Program)
    - From Boas, 1939 June 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 June 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 July 1; 1p.
  - Jackson, A.V. Williams (Box 46)
    - 1906 Mar 13
    - From Boas, 1906 May 8
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 9
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 9
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1896 May 23
    - To Boas, 1896 May 30
    - To Boas, 1900 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 May 5
    - To Boas, 1921 Apr. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Apr. 23; 1p.
  - Jackson, Gardner P. (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1924 June 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 June 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 June 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Oct. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 May 31; 1p.
    - (Enc. Boas, F. to Smith, L.V. May 20, 1924 Smith, L.V. to Jackson, G.P. May 27, 1924), 1939 Mar. 6; 2p.
    - (Enc: Jackson, G. to Rodman, S.J. Mar. 4, 1939), 1939 Apr. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 June 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 26; 2p.
    - G. Jackson -- to S.J. Rodman, 1939 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Jackson, Gardner, Mar. 6, 1939)
    - G. Jackson -- from L.V. Smith, 1924 May 27
  - Jackson, Henry (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1905 Mar. 29
  - Jackson, R.H. (Box 46)
    - R.H. Jackson -- from the Christian Front., 1939 Dec.
  - Jacob, F. (Box 46)
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 21; 1p.
  - Jacobi, Abraham (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1880 Mar. 31
    - From Boas, 1882 Jan. 2
    - From Boas, 1882 Apr. 10
    - From Boas, 1882 Apr. 12
    - From Boas, 1882 Nov. 26
    - From Boas, 1883 Feb. 8; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1883 May 2; 7p.
    - From Boas, 1883 May 9; 5p.
    - From Boas, 1885 Jan. 1
    - From Boas, 1885 Jan. 18; 7p.
    - From Boas, 1885 Jan. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1885 Jan. 13; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1885 Feb. 12; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1885 Feb. 25; 2p.
    - also see C.P. Daly, 1896 Mar. 12
    - From Boas, 1904 May 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1904 May 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1904 Oct. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 24
    - From Boas, 1909 Sept. 2; 5p.
    - From Boas, 1909 Sept. 9; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1909 Oct. 14
    - From Boas, 1909 Oct. 22
    - From Boas, 1909 Nov. 5; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1910 Jan. 14
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 29
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 25; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1882 Apr.?
    - To Boas, 1883 May 29
    - To Boas, 1885 Jan. 17; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1885 Mar. 16
    - To Boas, 1885 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1905 Feb. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 17
    - To Boas, 1915 Aug. 7
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 25; 1p.
    - A.J. -- from Sophie Boas, 1882 July 22
    - A, Jacobi -- from N.S. Spencer, 1911 Nov. 22
  - Jacobi, Ludwig (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1910 June 2
    - To Boas, 1910 June 1; 1p.
  - Jacobs, Joseph (Box 46)
    - From Boas, 1903 Oct. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1903 Nov. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Oct. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Oct. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Nov. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Mar. 3
  - Jacobs, Max (Box 47)
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 May 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 26; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. (open letter), Dec. 8, 193?
  - Jacobs, Melville (Box 47)
    - From Boas, 1926 July 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Aug. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 May 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Apr. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Apr. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 June 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 7; telegram
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 8; telegram
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 9; telegram
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Dec. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Apr. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Apr. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 May 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 May 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Jan. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Jan. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 May 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 May 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 June 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 July 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 May 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 June 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Sept. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 May 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 May 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 May 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 June 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 June 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 July 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 July 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Aug. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 May 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 May 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 May 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1938 May 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Dec. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Feb. 12; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1940 May 27; 1p.
    - (Enc: Boas, F. to Sieg, Lee P. May 27, 1940), 1940 June 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Dec. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1941 Apr. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 June 14; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 16; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 31; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Jan. 20; 2p.
    - See Boas, F. (open letter) Mar.9,1927., 1927 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Apr. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 July 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 July 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Oct. 6; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. (open letter) Oct. 10, 1928., 1928 Oct. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Nov. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Nov. 7; telegram
    - To Boas, 1928 Nov. 8; telegram
    - To Boas, 1928 Nov. 27; 2p.
    - To Boas (Monday), 1928 Dec.; 2p.
    - To Boas (Tuesday), 1928 Dec.; 2p.
    - To Boas (Wednesday), 1928 Dec.; 2p.
    - To Boas (Wednesday), 1928 Dec.; 2p.
    - To Boas (Thursday), 1928 Dec.; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Apr. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 July 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 4; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 29; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec.
    - (See Boas, F. to Shapr, W. 1931), 1931 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 June 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec.
    - (See Boas, F. (open letter) 1932), 1933 Jan. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 20; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 July 14; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 July 22; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 July 31; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 13; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec.; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1933 end; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1933 end; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 end; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 8; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 May 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 June 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 June 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 July 1; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 6; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 23; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 June 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 June 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 20; teleg.
    - To Boas, 1937 May 18; 1p.
      (Enc: List 4p.)
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Apr. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Apr. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 May 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 May 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Sept. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 July 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 6; 1p.
    - (Enc: Goethe, C.M. to Jacobs, M. Dec. 5, 1939), 1939 Dec. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 May 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 Apr. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 May 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1941 July 31; 1p.
    - M. Jacobs -- to R.W. Bryan, 1932 July 13; 1p.
    - M. Jacobs -- from R.W. Bryan, 1932 July 20
    - M. Jacobs -- from C.M. Goethe, 1939 Dec. 5
    - (Enc. with Jacobs, M., Dec. 6, 1939)
    - M. Jacobs -- from D. Thomson, 1927 Oct. 11
    - (Enc. with Thomson, D., Oct. 12, 1927)
  - Jacobs, Milt (Box 47)
    - Milt Jacobs -- to Dr. F. Bray, 1935 or 1936 Nov. 22; 2p.
  - Jacobs, Paula (Box 47)
    - From Boas, 1935 Aug. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Mar. 18; 2p.
    - See Boas, F. (open letter) Dec. 8, 1938, 1939 Apr. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Aug. 1; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. 26; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. (open letter), Nov. 11, 1940
    - P. Jacobs -- from M.F. Ashley-Montagu, 1937 Aug. 16
    - P. Jacobs -- from E.C. Parsons, 1936 Aug. 26
    - P. Jacobs -- from G.A. Reichard, 1938 Dec. 4
    - P. Jacobs -- from Roberto Rendueles, 1938 Feb. 2
    - P. Jacobs -- from K.G. Wendriner, 1935 Aug. 9
  - Jacobs, Philip P. (Box 47)
    - To Boas, 1910 June 29
    - To Boas, 1910 June 30; 4p.
  - Jacobson, Arthur C. (Box 47)
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Nov. 3; 1p.
  - Jacottet, P.N. (Box 47)
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1922 Dec. 27; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 5; 2p.
  - Jaegendorf, M.A. (Box 47)
    - From Boas, 1909 May 6
    - (See Boas, F. to Rappapart May 6, 1909), 1909 May 15
    - From Boas, 1909 May 22
    - From Boas, 1909 May 25
    - From Boas, 1909 June 29
    - From Boas, 1909 July 1
    - From Boas, 1909 July 2
    - To Boas, 1909 May 3
    - To Boas, 1934 June 19; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Solmsen, F. to Dunn, L.C., June 24, 1934)
  - Jaffé, A. (Box 47)
    - From Boas, 1926 June 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 June 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 June 7; 1p.
  - Jaffé, M. (Box 47)
    - From Boas, 1926 June 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 June 27; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept. 6; 1p.